My work is about the behaviors that we all engage in unconsciously,
عملي يدور حول السلوكيات التي ننغمس فيها جميعنا بغير وعي
on a collective level.
على مستوى جماعي.
And what I mean by that, it's the behaviors
والذي أقصده بذلك، السلوكيات
that we're in denial about,
التي نحن في حالة إنكار لها،
and the ones that operate below the surface of our daily awareness.
والتي تعمل أسفل سطح وعينا اليومي.
And as individuals, we all do these things, all the time, everyday.
كأفراد، نحن نفعل هذه الأشياء، في كل الأوقات، كل يوم.
It's like when you're mean to your wife
مثل عندما تكون لئيماً تجاه زوجتك
because you're mad at somebody else.
لأنك غاضب من أحدهم.
Or when you drink a little too much at a party, just out of anxiety.
أو عندما تشرب قليلاً بعد في حفلة بسبب القلق.
Or when you overeat because your feelings are hurt, or whatever.
أو عندما تنفعل بشدة لأن مشاعرك مجروحة، أو مهما يكن.
And when we do these kind of things,
و عندما نفعل هذا النوع من الأشياء،
when 300 million people do unconscious behaviors,
عندما 300 مليون شخص يفعلون سلوكيات اللاوعي،
then it can add up to a catastrophic consequence
سيكون ممكنناً أن يتراكم إلى نتيجة مفجعة
that nobody wants, and no one intended.
لا يريدها أحد، و لم يقصدها أحد.
And that's what I look at with my photographic work.
و هذا الذي أنظر إليه في عملي التصويري.
This is an image I just recently completed, that is --
هذه صورة أكملتها حديثاً، وهي بحيث
when you stand back at a distance,
عندما تقف مسافة إلى الخلف،
it looks like some kind of neo-Gothic, cartoon image
تبدو كأنها نوع من أنواع صور الرسم القوطي الحديث
of a factory spewing out pollution.
عن مصنع يفيض بالتلوث.
And as you get a little bit closer,
و كلما اقتربت قليلاً،
it starts looking like lots of pipes, like maybe a chemical plant,
تبدو كأعداد كبيرة من الأنابيب، كمعمل كيميائي ربما،
or a refinery, or maybe a hellish freeway interchange.
أو مصفاة، أو ربما تقاطع شارع عام رهيب.
And as you get all the way up close,
وكلما اقتربت أكثر،
you realize that it's actually made of lots and lots of plastic cups.
تدرك أنها في الأصل مجموعة كبيرة جداً من الأكواب البلاستيكية.
And in fact, this is one million plastic cups,
و الحقيقة أنها مليون كوب بلاستيكي،
which is the number of plastic cups that are used on airline flights
و هو عدد الأكواب البلاستكية التي تستخدم في رحلات خطوط الطيران
in the United States every six hours.
في الولايات المتحدة كل ست ساعات.
We use four million cups a day on airline flights,
نحن نستخدم 4 ملايين كوب يومياً في رحلات خطوط الطيران،
and virtually none of them are reused or recycled.
وفعلياً لا يعاد استخدام أو تدوير أحدها؛
They just don't do that in that industry.
لا يفعلون ذلك في تلك الصناعة.
Now, that number is dwarfed
الآن ذلك العدد يتضاءل
by the number of paper cups we use every day,
بعدد الأكواب الورقية التي نستخدمها يوميا،ً
and that is 40 million cups a day for hot beverages,
وذلك 40 مليون كوب يومياً للمشروبات الساخنة،
most of which is coffee.
معظمها قهوة.
I couldn't fit 40 million cups on a canvas,
لم أستطع وضع 40 مليون كوب على اللوحة،
but I was able to put 410,000. That's what 410,000 cups looks like.
ولكن استطعت أن أضع 410،000 كوب. وهكذا يبدو 410،000 كوب.
That's 15 minutes of our cup consumption.
هذا 15 دقيقة من استهلاكنا للأكواب.
And if you could actually stack up that many cups in real life,
وإذا أستطعت تكديس هذا العدد من الأكواب في الواقع ،
that's the size it would be.
هذا هو الحجم الذي سيكون عليه.
And there's an hour's worth of our cups.
وهذا هو ما يساوي ساعة من أكوابنا.
And there's a day's worth of our cups.
وهذا هو ما يساوي يوم من أكوابنا.
You can still see the little people way down there.
لايزال بإمكانك روؤية الناس صغاراً في الأسفل بعيداً هناك.
That's as high as a 42-story building,
هذا بعلو بناية ذات 42 طابق.
and I put the Statue of Liberty in there as a scale reference.
و وضعت تمثال الحرية هناك كمرجع للقياس.
Speaking of justice, there's another phenomenon going on in our culture
بالحديث عن العدالة، هناك ظاهرة مستمرة في ثقافتنا
that I find deeply troubling, and that is that America, right now,
و التي أجدها تدعو للاضطراب، وهي أن أمريكا الآن
has the largest percentage of its population in prison
لديها أكبر نسبة من سكانها في السجون
of any country on Earth.
من أية دولة في الأرض.
One out of four people, one out of four humans in prison
واحد من أربعة أشخاص، واحد من أربعة من البشر في السجن
are Americans, imprisoned in our country.
أمريكيين، مسجونين في دولتنا.
And I wanted to show the number.
و أردت أن أريكم هذا العدد.
The number is 2.3 million Americans were incarcerated in 2005.
العدد هو 2.3 مليون أمريكي احتجزوا في 2005.
And that's gone up since then, but we don't have the numbers yet.
وهذا العدد ارتفع من ذلك الحين، ولكن ليس لدينا الأرقام بعد.
So, I wanted to show 2.3 million prison uniforms,
لذلك أردت أن أعرض 2.3 مليون زي سجين،
and in the actual print of this piece,
وبحجم الطباعة لهذه القطعة،
each uniform is the size of a nickel on its edge.
كل زي هو بحجم النيكل وهو على حافته.
They're tiny. They're barely visible as a piece of material,
هم صغار جداً، بالكاد يظهرون كجزء من مادة،
and to show 2.3 million of them required a canvas
ولعرض 2.3 مليون منهم يستلزم لوحة
that was larger than any printer in the world would print.
كبيرة كفاية لأية آلة طباعة في العالم لتطبعها.
And so I had to divide it up into multiple panels
ولذلك كان عليّ أن أقسمها إلى عدة ألواح
that are 10 feet tall by 25 feet wide.
طول كلٍ منها 10 أقدام وعرضها 25 قدم.
This is that piece installed in a gallery in New York --
هذه هي اللوحة التي وضعت في صالة عرض في نيويورك؛
those are my parents looking at the piece.
هؤلاء هم والديّ ينظرون إلى اللوحة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Every time I look at this piece,
كلما أنظر إلى هذه اللوحة،
I always wonder if my mom's whispering to my dad,
أتسائل إذا كانت أمي تهمس إلى أبي،
"He finally folded his laundry."
"أخيراً لقد طوى الغسيل."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I want to show you some pieces now that are about addiction.
أريد أن أريكم الآن بعض القطع عن الإدمان.
And this particular one is about cigarette addiction.
وهذه بالذات عن إدمان السجائر.
I wanted to make a piece that shows the actual number of Americans
أردت أن أعمل لوحة تظهر العدد الفعلي للأمريكيين
who die from cigarette smoking.
الذي يموتون من التدخين.
More than 400,000 people die in the United States every year
أكثر من 400,000 شخص ماتوا في الولايات المتحدة كل عام
from smoking cigarettes.
من تدخين السجائر.
And so, this piece is made up of lots and lots of boxes of cigarettes.
و هذه اللوحة عبارة عن الكثير الكثير من علب السجائر.
And, as you slowly step back,
وكلما تخطو ببطء إلى الوراء،
you see that it's a painting by Van Gogh, called "Skull with Cigarette."
يكمن أن ترى أنها لوحة لفان جوغ تسمى "جمجمة مع سيجارة."
It's a strange thing to think about, that on 9/11,
انه شيء غريب يدعو للتفكير، أنه في 11\9،
when that tragedy happened, 3,000 Americans died.
عندما حدثت الكارثة، 3,000 أمريكي ماتوا،
And do you remember the response?
و هل تتذكر رد الفعل ؟
It reverberated around the world,
لقد دوى حول العالم،
and will continue to reverberate through time.
و سوف يدوي عبر الزمن.
It will be something that we talk about in 100 years.
سيكون شيئاً نتحدث عنه لمئة عام.
And yet on that same day, 1,100 Americans died from smoking.
ومع ذلك و في اليوم نفسه، 1,100 أمريكي ماتوا من التدخين.
And the day after that, another 1,100 Americans died from smoking.
واليوم الذي تلاه، 1,100 أمريكي ماتوا من التدخين.
And every single day since then, 1,100 Americans have died.
وكل يوم من ذلك الحين، 1,100 أمريكي يموتون،
And today, 1,100 Americans are dying from cigarette smoking.
واليوم، 1,100 أمريكي يموتون من تدخين السجائر.
And we aren't talking about it -- we dismiss it.
ولكننا لا نتحدث عنه، بل ننصرف عنه.
The tobacco lobby, it's too strong.
جماعات التبغ، أنها قوية جداً.
We just dismiss it out of our consciousness.
نحن نصرف ذلك من وعينا فقط.
And knowing what we know about the destructive power of cigarettes,
ومعرفة مانعرف اليوم عن قوة السجائر المدمرة،
we continue to allow our children, our sons and daughters,
مازلنا نسمح لأطفالنا، أولادنا، و بناتنا،
to be in the presence of the influences that start them smoking.
أن يكونوا متواجدين حول المؤثرات التي تجعلهم يبدأون بالتدخين.
And this is what the next piece is about.
وهذا هو الذي تدور حوله اللوحة التالية.
This is just lots and lots of cigarettes: 65,000 cigarettes,
هذه الكثير الكثير من السجائر: 65,000 سجارة،
which is equal to the number of teenagers
وهو عدد مساوي لعدد المراهقين
who will start smoking this month, and every month in the U.S.
الذين بدأوا بالتدخين هذا الشهر، و كل شهر في الولايات المتحدة.
More than 700,000 children in the United States aged 18 and under
أكثر من 700,000 طفل في الولايات المتحدة أعمارهم من 18 سنة وأقل
begin smoking every year.
يبدأون بالتدخين كل عام.
One more strange epidemic in the United States
معضلة أخرى غريبة في الولايات المتحدة
that I want to acquaint you with
التي أريد منكم أن تتعرفوا عليها
is this phenomenon of abuse and misuse of prescription drugs.
هي ظاهرة سوء استخدام الأدوية الموصوفة.
This is an image I've made out of lots and lots of Vicodin.
هذه الصورة التي كونتها من الكثير الكثير من الفايكودين--
Well, actually, I only had one Vicodin
حسناً، فعلياً كان لدي فايكودين واحد
that I scanned lots and lots of times.
نسخته عدة عدة مرات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And so, as you stand back, you see 213,000 Vicodin pills,
وكلما تراجعتم للخلف ترون 213,000 حبة فايكودين،
which is the number of hospital emergency room visits
و هو عدد الزيارات غرفة الطوارئ في المستشفى
yearly in the United States,
سنوياً في الولايات المتحدة،
attributable to abuse and misuse of prescription painkillers
معوزاً إلى سوء استخدام مخففات الألم الموصوفة
and anti-anxiety medications.
وأدوية مضادات القلق.
One-third of all drug overdoses in the U.S. --
ثلث الجرع الزائدة للأدوية في الولايات المتحدة --
and that includes cocaine, heroin, alcohol, everything --
وهذا يتضمن الكوكايين، الهرويين، الكحول، وكل شيء --
one-third of drug overdoses are prescription medications.
ثلث الجرع الزائدة للأدوية هي أدوية موصوفة.
A strange phenomenon.
ظاهرة غريبة.
This is a piece that I just recently completed
وهذه لوحة أكملتها حديثاً
about another tragic phenomenon. And that is the phenomenon,
عن ظاهرة مأسوية أخرى. وهي ظاهرة
this growing obsession we have with breast augmentation surgery.
هاجسنا المتنامي لعمليات تكبير الصدر.
384,000 women, American women, last year
384,000 إمرأة، إمرأة أمريكية، العام الماضي
went in for elective breast augmentation surgery.
خضعوا لعملية تكبير صدر اختيارية.
It's rapidly becoming the most popular high school graduation gift,
لقد أصبحت وبشكل سريع الهدية الأكثر رواجاً للتخرج من الثانوية ،
given to young girls who are about to go off to college.
تعطى للفتيات الصغيرات اللواتي سيلتحقن بالكلية.
So, I made this image out of Barbie dolls,
لذلك عملت هذه اللوحة من دمى باربي،
and so, as you stand back you see this kind of floral pattern,
و كلما تراجعتم للخلف ترون نوع من النقشة النباتية،
and as you get all the way back, you see 32,000 Barbie dolls,
وكلما تراجعتم للخلف تماماً، ترون 32,000 دمية باربي،
which represents the number of breast augmentation surgeries
جميعها ترمز إلى عدد عمليات تكبير الصدر
that are performed in the U.S. each month.
التي تتم في الولايات المتحدة كل شهر.
The vast majority of those are on women under the age of 21.
الأكثرية الكاسحة هي لنساء تقل أعمارهن عن 21 سنة.
And strangely enough, the only plastic surgery
و الغريب أن العملية التجميلية الوحيدة
that is more popular than breast augmentation is liposuction,
التي تلقى رواجاً بعد تكبير الصدر هي شفط الدهون،
and most of that is being done by men.
و معظم ذلك يقوم بأدائه رجال.
Now, I want to emphasize that these are just examples.
الآن، أريد أن أشدد أن هذه فقط أمثلة.
I'm not holding these out as being the biggest issues.
أنا لا أبينها على أنها أكبر المسائل.
They're just examples.
هذه فقط أمثلة.
And the reason that I do this, it's because I have this fear
و السبب الذي يدفعني إلى ذلك هو لإني عندي هذا الخوف
that we aren't feeling enough as a culture right now.
من أننا لا نستشعر كثقافة بما يكفي الآن .
There's this kind of anesthesia in America at the moment.
هناك نوع من الخدر في أمريكا في الوقت الحالي.
We've lost our sense of outrage, our anger and our grief
لقد فقدنا إحساسنا بالحنق، غضبنا وألمنا
about what's going on in our culture right now,
ومايجري في ثقافتنا الآن،
what's going on in our country,
بما يجري في دولتنا،
the atrocities that are being committed in our names around the world.
الفظاعة التي يتم ارتكابها حول العالم باسمنا.
They've gone missing; these feelings have gone missing.
لقد اختفت؛ تلك المشاعر لقد اختفت.
Our cultural joy, our national joy is nowhere to be seen.
متعتنا الثقافية، متعتنا الوطنية لا ترى في أي مكان.
And one of the causes of this, I think,
وواحدة من هذه الأسباب، أعتقد،
is that as each of us attempts to build this new kind of worldview,
أنه كل واحد منا يحاول بناء نوع من رؤية عالمية،
this holoptical worldview, this holographic image
هذه الرؤية العالمية الهولوبتكالية ، هذه الصورة الهولوغرافية
that we're all trying to create in our mind
التي نحاول أن نخلقها في عقولنا
of the interconnection of things: the environmental footprints
عن الصلات المتداخلة من أشياء: البصمة البيئية
1,000 miles away of the things that we buy;
1,000 ميل بعيداً عن الأشياء التي نشتريها؛
the social consequences 10,000 miles away
النتائج الاجتماعية 10,000 ميل بعيداً
of the daily decisions that we make as consumers.
عن القرارات اليومية التي نتخذها كمستهلكين.
As we try to build this view,
ونحن في محاولة بناء هذه الرؤية،
and try to educate ourselves about the enormity of our culture,
و محاولة تعليم أنفسنا عن شناعة ثقافتنا،
the information that we have to work with is these gigantic numbers:
المعلومات التي يجب أن نتعامل معها هي هذه الأرقام المهولة:
numbers in the millions, in the hundreds of millions,
أعداد بالملايين، بمئات الملايين،
in the billions and now in the trillions.
بالمليارات و الترلليونات.
Bush's new budget is in the trillions, and these are numbers
مزانية بوش بالترليارات، وهذه الأرقام
that our brain just doesn't have the ability to comprehend.
التي لايمكن لعقولنا أن تستوعبها.
We can't make meaning out of these enormous statistics.
لا يمكن أن ندرك معنى هذه الإحصاءات الكبيرة.
And so that's what I'm trying to do with my work,
وهذا هو الذي أحول أن أفعله في عملي،
is to take these numbers, these statistics
أن أخذ هذه الأرقام، هذه الإحصاءات
from the raw language of data, and to translate them
من لغة المعلومات الأولية، و ترجمتهم
into a more universal visual language, that can be felt.
إلى لغة مرئية عالمية أكثر، يمكن أن يشعر بها.
Because my belief is, if we can feel these issues,
لأن إيماني هو إذا كان بإمكاننا الشعور بهذه المسائل،
if we can feel these things more deeply,
إذا كان بإمكاننا الشعور بهذه الأشياء بعمق،
then they'll matter to us more than they do now.
فسيهموننا أكثر من الآن.
And if we can find that,
و إذا كان بإمكاننا العثور على ذلك،
then we'll be able to find, within each one of us,
فسيكون باستطاعتنا العثور في شخص كل منا
what it is that we need to find to face the big question,
الشيء الذي نحتاج للعثور عليه لمواجهة السؤال الكبير،
which is: how do we change?
الذي هو: كيف نتغير؟
That, to me, is the big question that we face as a people right now:
هذا بالنسبة لي هو السؤال الكبير الذي يواجهنا كـأناس الآن:
how do we change? How do we change as a culture,
كيف نتغير؟ كيف نتغيركثقافة،
and how do we each individually take responsibility
وكيف يتحمّل كل فرد مسؤولية
for the one piece of the solution that we are in charge of,
جزء من التغيير الذي نحن مسؤولون عنه،
and that is our own behavior?
وهو سلوكنا نحن؟
My belief is that you don't have to make yourself bad
إيماني هو أنك لا تحتاج أن تجعل نفسك سيئاً
to look at these issues.
للنظر في هذه المسائل.
I'm not pointing the finger at America in a blaming way.
أنا لا ألقي باللوم على أمريكا.
I'm simply saying, this is who we are right now.
أنا ببساطة أقول هكذا نحن الآن.
And if there are things that we see
وإذا كانت هناك أشياء نراها
that we don't like about our culture,
ولاتعجبنا في ثقافتنا،
then we have a choice.
فلدينا خيار.
The degree of integrity that each of us can bring to the surface,
درجة الأمانة التي يقدمها كل شخص منا،
to bring to this question, the depth of character that we can summon,
لطرح هذا السؤال، العمق في الشخصية التي يمكن أن نستجمعها
as we show up for the question of how do we change --
ونحن نحضر لهذا السؤال عن كيف نتغير.
it's already defining us as individuals and as a nation,
أنه يحددنا بالفعل كأفراد و كأمة ،
and it will continue to do that, on into the future.
وسيستمر في فعل ذلك إلى المستقبل.
And it will profoundly affect the well-being, the quality of life
وسيؤثر بعمق على الرفاهية، على نوعية الحياة
of the billions of people
لمليارات من الناس
who are going to inherit the results of our decisions.
الذين سيرثون نتائج قراراتنا.
I'm not speaking abstractly about this,
أنا لا أتحدث عن هذا على نحوٍ نظري،
I'm speaking -- this is who we are in this room,
أنا أتحدث -- ها نحن في هذه القاعة.
right now, in this moment.
الآن هي اللحظة.
Thank you and good afternoon.
شكراً ومساء الخير.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)